<form theme="light" version="1.1">
	<label>Splunk Dashboards</label>

	<row>
		<panel>
			<html>
				<img src="/static/app/SSPHP/images/dfe.png" />
			</html>
		</panel>
	</row>

	<row>
		<panel>
			<html>
				<h1>
					<b>Intro to Service Security Posture Hardening Programme</b>
				</h1>
			</html>
		</panel>
	</row>

	<row>
		<panel>
			<html>
				<h2 style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px">
					<b>Dashboards</b>
				</h2>

				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px"> Microsoft has a default set of
					policies which they determine to represent 'best practice' configuration
					guidelines for the Azure estate; these are packaged up in the Defender for Cloud
					service. MS frquently runs assessment tests against the
					estate to establish where we might have broken their recommendations, and offer
					advice on how to remediate the discrepancies. In SSPHP, the output from these
					assessments is collected together as Findings (our own name). Alerts are
					noteworthy events that have happened in the estate that have been triggered by a
					Microsoft policy.</p>
				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px"> Microsoft also exposes a number
					of Azure APIs which we use to understand the topology of the Azure estate - what
					tenancies,
					subscriptions and resource groups exist and what are their relationships. It
					also gives us a metadata about the Services that own the resources, although the
					lack of a common taxonomy has meant that we have had to improvise with our own
					rules to interpret the metadata.</p>
				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px"> The CIP tenancy has the best
					organised
					naming conventions which allow us to be sure about associating resources with
					Services. This uses a code called the 'Business Service Index' which allocates a
					unique ID to each Service and has a metadata marker for the subscriptions. For
					CIP, the code is a letter s followed by 3 numbers; the standard codes were given
					to us in a spreadsheet. Where necessary, for other tenancies, we have allocated
					our own codes, which begin with the letter p.</p>
				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px"> The dashboards invoke
					Role Base Access Control (RBAC). Every Splunk user has 1 or many 'roles'
					associated with their id, their roles defining what they can access in Splunk,
					SSPHP has been set up such that sc-admins can access data from all Services,
					whereas if the user's role includes their Business Service Index then they will
					only be able to see the data from that Service (in fact the Service dropdowns
					will be hidden from them).</p>
				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px"> It is important to note that the
					premise of
					SSPHP is to be Service aligned. The idea is to give the Services clarity on
					where they have potential security mis-configurations and drive the process of
					remediation, thus improving DfE's Security Posture. By organising all of the
					data by Service, each Service has a list of remdeiations organised by
					development area which should be more manageable in terms of driving and
					tracking remediation.</p>
				<br></br>

				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px">
					<b>Azure Findings Dashboard</b><br></br> This dashboard has 6 components : <table
						style="border:1px solid grey">
						<tr style="border:1px solid grey">
							<td style="border:1px solid grey; width:22%">Resources with High
								Findings</td>
							<td>Pie chart showing which Findings are the most widespread - have the
					most resources associated with them.</td>
						</tr>
						<tr style="border:1px solid grey">
							<td style="border:1px solid grey">Resource Groups with Most High
								Findings chart</td>
							<td>Pie chart showing which Resource Groups have the most Findings
					associated with them.</td>
						</tr>
						<tr style="border:1px solid grey">
							<td style="border:1px solid grey">Findings List</td>
							<td>List of all policy assessments that Azure Defender for Cloud ran
					against the estate that returned an 'Unhealthy' state, sorted with High severity
					at the top and by the Date when Microsoft first reported them.</td>
						</tr>
						<tr style="border:1px solid grey">
							<td style="border:1px solid grey">Findings By Resource</td>
							<td>List of Findings organised by Resource within Subscription and
					Resource Group. So if a single resource has multiple Findinfs associated with it
					then they will be listed together in this view.</td>
						</tr>
						<tr style="border:1px solid grey">
							<td style="border:1px solid grey">Resources By Finding</td>
							<td>List of Findings with all the resources that have triggered each of
					them.
								This should help to prioritise the order in which to tackle
					remediation of each Finding.</td>
						</tr>
						<tr style="border:1px solid grey">
							<td style="border:1px solid grey">Changes Since Checkpoint</td>
							<td>A 'Checkpoint' is time and date from which a Service has chosen to
					measure changes to the Findings that remain outstanding.
							</td>
						</tr>
					</table>
					<br></br>
				</p>

				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px">
					<b>Azure Alerts Dashboard</b>
					<br></br> Whilst Findings are conceptually things
					that 'are', such as a mis-configuration <u>in</u> the estate (maybe a publicly
					available storage blob, for example), Alerts are things that have happened <u>to</u>
					the estate (maybe the exfiltratition of a file). Microsoft has rules that it
					runs frequently against the Azure estate and notifys us of all Alerts detected.<br></br>
				</p>

				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px">
					<b>Azure Metrics Dashboard</b>
					<br></br> The intention is that this dashboard
					will become a place where SMT can view progress and understand risk by viewing
					metrics relating to the Findings in the Azure estate. <br></br> Initially the
					dashboard only holds one chart - Security Scores by Subscription... Microsoft
					assigns a score to each policy assessment that it runs, and credits each
					resource with the score based on whether that resource is Healthy or Unhealthy.
					So a high score is good, and low is bad. This chart shows the total security
					score for every DfE Subscription; the data in purple is simply the inverse of
					that in pink to simplify the view... so Subscritpions at the right-hand side
					have low security scores and are bad, whereas on the left side they have high
					security score which is good.<br></br>
				</p>

				<p style="line-height: 1.5em; margin-bottom: 15px">
					<b>Azure Resources Dashboard</b>
					<br></br> This dashboard is there to facilitate
					triage... it allows you to key in the name of a Resource Group which exists
					somewhere in the DfE Azure estate, and it will return details of which Tenancy
					and Subscription that Resource Group lives in, and any metadata around the
					Service and individuals who own it. 
					<br></br>The input test box supports * as a wildcard character.<br></br>
				</p>
			</html>
		</panel>
	</row>
</form>